Guide to the Renew Media/Rockefeller Foundation Fellowships in New Media Art 2003-2004.
Renew Media/Rockefeller Foundation Fellowships in New Media Art 2003-2004
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Renew Media/Rockefeller Foundation Fellowships in New Media Art 2003-2004.
6673
Renew Media, Rockefeller Foundation and National Video Resources.
16 cubic ft.
Printed material, CDs, digital media
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
The collection consists of artist's files submitted to sponsors the Rockefeller Foundation and National Video Resources in application for New Media Fellowships.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
The collection consists of artists' files submitted to the Rockefeller Foundation and National Video Resources, who sponsored the New Media Fellowships. The files comprise artistic proposals and outlines, individual artists' curricula vitae, recommendation and reference letters, and supporting digital and media art on CDs or DVDs.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Renew Media, Rockefeller Foundation and National Video Resources.
Subjects:
Electronic records.; Digital art.; Interactive video.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Links to the artist's webpages are not maintained. The URLs for these projects are provided, but many no longer go anywhere. You may have success finding archived versions of them using the Internet Archive Wayback Machine, http://web.archive.org
Some digital content has been archived by Cornell and that content can be found by following the links labeled "Link to archived internet material."
SERIES LIST
Series I. Rockefeller New Media Fellowships 2003
Boxes 1-4
Series II. Rockefeller New Media Fellowships 2004
Boxes 5-7
Series III. Rockefeller New Media Fellowships 2005
Boxes 8-10
Series IV. Rockefeller New Media Fellowships 2006
Boxes 11-13
Series V. Rockefeller New Media Fellowships 2007
Boxes 14-15
Series VI. Rockefeller New Media Fellowships 2008
Box 16
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Rockefeller New Media Fellowships 2003
  - Project Proposal: "Come" (Stages of pleasure), Aranda, Julieta (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Link to archived internet material.
    - Documentation, with illustrations
    - Video:
      - Mol
      - A Story of Rats (excerpt)
      - A Story of Rats (supplemental documentation)
      - It's is Colder Inside (excerpt)
    - CD-ROM:
      - Safety Instruction (5 images) (damaged?)
      - Safety Instruction (audio track)
  - Project Proposal: The Ideoplastic Materialization of Eva C., Beloff, Zoe (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Drawing:
      - The Influencing Machine of Miss Natalijaa, 2 copies, Oversized folder (Box 85)
    - Video:
      - The Influencing Machine of Miss Natalija A
      - Shadow Land or Light from the Other Side
      - The Influencing Machine of Miss Natalija A Slides
    - 3-D Glasses, 2 pair
  - Project Proposal: Virtual Web: Global Interactive Spectacle (includes text instructions and 2 installation diagrams in color), Bowditch, Rachel (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Perspective Diagrams, 2 sets
    - Video:
      - Selected Work 1996-2002
      - A Woman's Place
      - Vessel performs Transfix in Central Park
  - Project Proposal: Eon (includes installation diagram), Brixey, Shawn (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Video:
      - Sample Work 2 & Supp. (Includes demos "Eon," "Chimera Obscura," "Liquiescence," "Secret Agents")
    - CD-ROM:
      - Sample Work 1
    - Website: (May no longer function)
      - Research Website
  - Project Proposal: ! (punctum), Burgess, Martha (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Play List/Script (of sample work Nocturne, Opus 23, "Moonlighting")
    - Video:
      - Nocturne, Opus 23, "Moonlighting"
    - CD-ROM:
      - Works 2000-200 (very slow to load)
  - Project Proposal, Joyce Noire, Castro, Jorge (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Video:
      - Complete Works on Video 1994-2002
      - Samples (includes Palindro(includesme ++, Sticky Ioopa-Hoopa,, R.E.S)
    - CD-ROM (Mac):
      - Videos + Software + Macintosh
  - Project Proposal: Visions from the Economy of Waste, Chan, Paul (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Video:
      - Sample Work 1 (includes doc of Happiness (finally)..., RE: The_Operation)
    - CD-ROM:
      - "Alternumeries"
    - Pamphlet:
      - Alternumeries
      - 2 small books/pamphlets
      - 1 large packet: photocopies of work samples
  - Project Proposal: Mixed Greens (part 3 of Queer Feast), Citron, Michelle (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - CD-ROM:
      - As American As Apple Pie
      - Cocktails & Appetizers
      - Jewish Looks (need Flash update?)
  - Project Proposal: Information Portraits Project, Coleman, Beth, and Howard Goldkrand (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - CD-ROM:
      - Mobile Stealth Unit, Sculpture Diagram
      - Soundlab/Flav-o-Pac
      - Soundlab/TiH not with others?
    - Website: (May no longer function)
      - Vernacular Software
  - Project Proposal: Need_X_Change, Daniel, Sharon (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - CD-ROM:
      - Need_X_Change
      - Narrative Contingencies
  - Project Proposal: A Small Migration (includes installation diagram/floorplan), Decker, Shawn (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Video:
      - Sound Installation Documentation (includes doc of Scratch Studies,The Night Sounds, Wire Field)
  - Project Proposal: Peoples' Data Exchange Network (includes installation diagram), Drew, Jesse (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - CD-ROM:
      - Teller Machine: An electronic critique of the global economy
  - Project Proposal: NON-STOP (includes floorplan, gestural "script" and mechanical draft of sculpture), Dron, Alejandro (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Video:
      - Tet
      - Interactive Kinetic Sculptures (includes doc of Fold-Unfold, RUAS, ESH, CROK, SHIN)
      - Non-Stop
    - Catalogues, 5
    - Floor Plan (2 copies, photo-prints and high resolution computer prints of script and draft)
    - Post Card
    - CD-ROM:
      - Website (need connection; many links no longer active)
    - 9 Slides
    - Catalog:
      - Dron: Kinetic Interactive Sculptures
    - Gallery Guide:
      - Dron: Painting Reliefs Sculptures
      - Tet
  - Project Proposal: Counterface (includes floorplans for Counterface and Skip), Even, Tirtza (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Video:
      - Dayam Al Hurbano (Existing On Its Ruins)
      - Sample Works: Occupied Territory, Slip, Counterface
    - CD-ROM:
      - Occupied Territory Web-Site
      - Occupied Territory (2002)
  - Project Proposal: Animal, Vegetable, Minearal (includes diagram and screen shots), Feingold, Ken (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Video:
      - "If/Then' and 'Self Portrait as the Center of the Universe'
    - Installation Diagram (letter size color prints, 4 copies)
  - Project Proposal: The Peoples' Portrait (includes visualization), Ga, Zhang (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Images, print, 2 sets (1 b/w, 1 color)
    - Website (images):
      - World Leaders, From Distance, with Eyes Squinted
      - Etant donnés...
      - That Discreet Charm of the Bourgeoisie
  - Project Proposal: New Negrotopia (2 copies), Hargest, Tana (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - CD-ROM:
      - Bitter Nigger Inc.
    - Slides (not received)
    - Full Project Budget
  - Project Proposal: 8 (includes instructions for website Al-Jahiz and alpha prototype of game), Harvey, Auriea (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - CD-ROM:
      - 8 Game Prototype, 2 copies? (to review CDs) (PC only)
      - Samples, 2 copies? (to review CDs) (includes websites http://entropy8zuper.org/drafts/al-hajiz and http://eden.garden1.1.projects.sfmoma.org)
    - Website: (May no longer function)
      - http://tale-of-tales.com/8/private (username: vip password: aceofspaces)
  - Project Proposal: AgentRuby.com Phase 4, Hershman, Lynn (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Images, 2 sets
    - E-mail Correspondences re: Turing Institute Loebner Prize
    - 1 Slide
    - Video:
      - Difference Engine 3
    - Website: (May no longer function)
      - http://www.agentruby.com
  - Project Proposal: Light Conversation (includes installation diagram for Light Conversation and Nosce Te Ipsum), Holmes, Tiffany (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Video:
      - Video Documentation: Nosce Te Ipsum, Japanese versions, Follow the Mouse, Fishbowl, Bearhunt
  - Project Proposal: Feral Robotic Dogs, Jeremijenko, Natalie (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Website: (May no longer function)
      - http://entity.eng.yale.edu/hat/animations/
  - Project Proposal: Infome Imager, Jevbratt, Lisa (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Project Descriptions, 2 copies
    - Website: (May no longer function)
      - http://jevbratt.com/mapping_the_web_infome/
      - http://www.c5corp.com/1to1
      - http://jevbratt.com/synchro_mail/unconscious_collective
  - Project Proposal: Tracing the Space Between Two People (includes installation diagram and sketches), Jones, Warren (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Video:
      - Tracing the Space Between Two People (includes doc of 16 People Watching the Same Thing, Seen and Not Seen, Love's Gaze, Drawing on the Clouds)
    - CD-ROM:
      - Tracing the Space Between Two People (includes portfolio and doc of Love's Gaze)
    - Images:
      - Attentional Funnels: Analyzing Normative Patterns of Visual Scanning and Quantifying Salience
    - Articles: samples of artist's published research in autism
  - Project Proposal: Terrain Machine (no print copy; on CD-ROM.), Klima, John (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - CD-ROM:
      - Work Samples (includes proposal and budget)
  - Project Proposal: CASE STUDY 9983 and CASEStudy 9983-B (includes mechanical diagram, apparatus diagram, floorplan, diagram and floorplan of installations Case Study 107, Case Study 309, Case Study 5510 and 5510-B), Knipp, Tammy (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Essay:
      - Virtual Environments: Psychosocial Happenings and the Theater of Life, 2 copies
    - Case Studies:
      - 9983-B, 2 copies, includes letter-sized photoprint of CS9983 sketch 5510 & 5510-5, 2 copies, includes articles and high-resolution color photoprints
    - Video:
      - "Case Study 107"
      - "Case Study 309"
      - "Case Study 5510 / Case Study 5510-B"
    - 5 Slides (3 of CS 107, 2 of 309)
    - 2 Slides of CS 5510 and 5510-B (Not Received)
  - Project Proposal, "Monochrome Landscapes", Kurgan, Laura (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - CD-ROM:
      - Sample Cameroon Imagery [PC only?]
      - Website (includes work samples)
  - Project Proposal: Sensing Data in Metaphorical Space, Legrady, George (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Images: 4 x color photoprint doc of installation "Sensing Speaking Space," 5 x doc of "Pockets Full of Memories," publicity stamps from PFOM show at Pompidou)
    - CD-ROM:
      - Sensing Speaking Space Prototype (Mac only)
      - Digital Interactive Installations (includes doc of "Eternal Summer," "Sensing Speaking Space," "Pockets Full of Memories," "Transitional Spaces," "Tracing," "A Sense of Place")
      - Projects 1973-2003
      - Interactive Installations 1997-2003
      - Pockets Full of Memories
  - Project Proposal: Micrographia (includes installation diagram and description of major projets), Levin, Golan (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - CD-ROM:
      - Dialtones a telesymphony (audio CD with video doc of concert)
      - 2003 Sample Work (includes "Audiovisual Environment Suite Softward," "Scribble Performance," "Dialtones," "RE:Mark (Hidden Worlds of Noise and Voice)," and Dialtones interview)
      - 2003 Sample Work - Backup
    - DVD:
      - ARS Electronica Active Score Music, Scribble, Small Fish Tale
      - AVES + software artwork
    - Book:
      - 4 x 4: Generative Design Beyond Photoshop (includes chapter by artist)
    - Installation Guide:
      - Hidden Worlds of Noise and Voice
  - Project Proposal: 25 Pieces of Paper (includes Text Organ diagram), Lewis, Jason (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Video:
      - I Know What You're Thinking
      - Nine
      - TextOrgan w/ It's Alive!
  - Project Proposal: Book of Hours (includes description and screenshots of websites "Grasping at Bits" and tree structure of B.o.H. interaction), Lichty, Patrick (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - CD-ROM:
      - Sprawl and Rtmark Information Kiosk Screensaver (2 copies)
    - Postcards:
      - Sprawl (2 copies)
    - Website: (May no longer function)
      - Grasping at Bits
  - Project Proposal: Empire of the Senseless, Ludin, Diane (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Video:
      - Genetic Response System 2.0
    - Zip Disk:
      - Diane Ludin Work Sample 2 & 3 (PC) (web screen grabs, includes "Harvesting the Net" and "Data Mirror: Touchable Video")
  - Project Proposal: Neen and Electronic Orphanage, includes list of websites created by the E.O., Manetas, Miltos (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - CD-ROM:
      - Neen Demo, 2 copies (PC)
    - Poster:
      - Neen (2 copies)
    - Book:
      - Mirrorsites 98 (paintings of new media electronics in use)
  - Project Proposal, "Soft Cinema OS" (includes installation diagrams and screen shots), Manovich, Lev (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Video:
      - Soft Cinema
    - Website: (May no longer function)
      - Anna and Andy
      - Little Movies
    - Image:
      - photocopy, screen shot
  - Project Proposal: Soft Rains (includes installation plan (text) and 2 diagrams), McCoy, Jennifer and Kevin (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Video:
      - Work Sample: Selected Recent Projects 2000-2002 (includes doc of installations "Pink Light," "Every Shot Every Episode," "Horror Chase")
  - Project Proposal: The Assassin's Dilemma, Napier, Mark (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - CD-ROM:
      - Work Sample (PC) (includes websites "Feed," "net.flag," "Waiting Room")
  - Project Proposal: Digital Debs (includes installation diagram), Obadike, Mendi and Keith (October 2004) (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Website: (May no longer function)
      - Interactions of Coloreds Color Check System
      - The Sour Thunder
      - Keeping Up Appearances, a Hypertextimonial
  - Project Proposal: The Oracle's Passage (includes installation diagrams), Panushka, Christine (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Video:
      - Marrow
      - Archive: Comings and Goings
    - CD-ROM:
      - Ivy Basket Web Site Demo (PC) (2 copies)
  - Project Proposal, "Bel-shaz-zar", Piper, Keith (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - CD-ROM:
      - Robot Bodies
      - Relocating the Remains
    - DVD:
      - Video Showreel
  - Project Proposal: Landscapes (includes diagram), Quraishi, Ibrahim (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Video:
      - Abandoned Shores
      - Rivage a l'abandon
    - CD-ROM:
      - Ring (doc of multimedia performance)
  - Project Proposal: still untitled, Simon, John F. Jr. (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Catalogue/Portfolio:
      - Art Report 2001
    - Completed Works Summaries, 2 copies
    - DVD:
      - "Channels"
      - "Artisit's Commentary: Working Process"
  - Project Proposal: The Brain Streaming Project (includes installation plan (text with color thumbnails)), Sobell, Nina (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Website: (May no longer function)
      - Web Séance: Brain Wave Drawings
      - Ebb & Flow
  - Project Proposal: GodsEye (includes installation diagrams, list of works with color thumbnails, sketches, criticism), Stern, Eddo (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - DVD:
      - Work Samples (includes "GodsEye elements" and doc of installations "Sheik Attack," "Tekken Torture Tournament," "Cockfight Arena")
  - Project Proposal: Flock Communication (working title) (includes diagrams of proposed installation and small diagrams of installations "Hum 157" and "untitled"), Stevenson, Vance (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Installation Diagrams, 2 copies
    - Video:
      - Hum 157 - Documentation and Untitled - Documentation
    - Audio CD:
      - Audio Sample
  - Project Proposal: Little NO (includes excerpts from script draft), Zurkow, Marina (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - CD-ROM:
      - Braingirl / Parthenogenesis
    - Budget for complete project
- Series II. Rockefeller New Media Fellowships 2004
  - Project Proposal: The Trial The Trail, Anstey, Josephine; and Dave Pape (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Video:
      - Sample Works 2003 (includes doc of The Thing Growing, PAAPAB, Falling Over You, The Trial The Trail teaser)
    - CD Rom:
      - Supplemental Material: The Thing Growing, Paapab, Falling Over You
  - Project Proposal: Citizen's Dilemma and AgaoraXchange, Bookchin, Natalie (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Website: (May no longer function)
      - The Intruder
      - Metapet
  - Project Proposal: City of Refuse(als) (includes color image of installation), Brown, Sheldon (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - CD-ROM:
      - Istoria Website
    - DVD:
      - Sheldon Brown: Works
  - Project Proposal: Just Voice, Daniel, Sharon (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - CD-ROM:
      - Untitled (Proposal portfolio, includes links and doc of past works)
    - Articles:
      - "Systems and Subjects, Redefining Public Art"
      - "Achieving an Aesthetics of Dignity in the Field of the Database"
  - Project Proposal: Drawing Voices (uses 2003 proposal form), Dongoski, Craig (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Video:
      - Drawing Voices
    - CD-ROM:
      - Drawing Voices, 2 copies (1 Mac, 1 PC)
      - Drawing Voices (audio)
      - Rock's Role (audio)
    - DVD:
      - Drawing Voices
  - Project Proposal: Spectropia (includes installation diagram, screenplay, tree structure of sample interactive diagram), Dove, Toni (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - CD-ROM:
      - Work Samples: Spectropia and Artificial Changelings
    - DVD:
      - Spectropia (scratched?)
      - Sally or The Bubble Burst
    - Video:
      - Sally or The Bubble Bust Demo
    - Catalog/Gallery Guide
    - Images:
      - color photoprints of installations Spectropia and Artificial Changelings, 2 sets
    - Articles:
      - press/criticism
  - Project Proposal: Offshore, Easterling, Keller (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - CD-ROM:
      - The High Line: Ploting NYC, 2 copies
      - Wildcards: a Game of Orgman, 2 copies
    - Articles:
      - "I Love DPRK: Cruise Ship Diplomacy in North Korea" (by artist)
      - "Tomato World" (by artist)
  - Project Proposal: Transformers (includes color cover sheet, diagram/floorplan of installation Mnemonic Devices, Dis-Ease, Dataskins and information about slides), Erickson, Christa (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - DVD:
      - Work Samples (includes doc of Mnemonic Devices, dataskins, Learning Distance, FormFitting, REPlay)
    - Slides:
      - 10 installation slides
  - Project Proposal: Habitat, Eshkar, Shelley (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - DVD:
      - Work Samples (includes doc of Rivalry, Pedestrian, Ghostcatching)
  - Project Proposal: Counterface (includes floorplan of installations Slip, Icarus, Counterface) Transcripts of interviews used for Counterface, Even, Tirtza (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Video:
      - Kayam Al Hurbano
      - Counterface
      - Tirtza Even
    - CD-ROM:
      - Occupied Territory
    - Slides:
      - 10 installation slides
  - Project Proposal: Traveling Corners/Esquinas Rodontes (includes installation floorplan), Ferrerra-Balanquet (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Essay:
      - "Interactive Cinema and Networking Narrative in Traveling Corners/Esquinas Rodontes"
    - Script excerpt from Traveling Corners
    - CD-ROM:
      - Traveling Corners (Mac)
      - Traveling Corners (PC)
      - Portfolio
    - DVD:
      - Esquinas Rodantes; Traveling Corners
    - Website: (May no longer function)
      - www.travelingcorners.com
      - www.travelingcorners/game/tc_game_portal.htm
      - www.moonradio.co.uk/moonradio_new/index.php
    - Texts:
      - Script/Voiceover excerpt (Traveling Corners) (duplicates part of proposal)
      - "Script for a game" (duplicates part of proposal)
    - Pamphlet:
      - Moon Radio Schedule,"Sex Food Politics"
  - Project Proposal: A Ritual Device for a Bionic Tea Ceremony (includes screen shots), Fisher, Ebon (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Portfolio:
      - "Overview of Works"
    - Poster:
      - Zoacodes: Soft Ethics for a Nervous World (2 copies)
      - Larval Zoacodes: Emergent Media Lifeforms (2 copies)
    - Supplemental images (b/w printouts), 2 sets
    - Articles packet:
      - "Extended Articles"
    - List of References
    - CD-ROM:
      - Video Documentation of Works olulO
    - Website: (May no longer function)
      - www.olulo.net
  - Project Proposal: [Familiar relativity] and [tethers] (includes installation diagrams for both), Flanagan, Mary (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Mini-CD-ROM:
      - Collection (PC)
    - Website: (May no longer function)
      - www.maryflanagan.com/search/searcho1.htm
    - Articles:
      - (photocopies of criticism and press)
  - Project Proposal: Mu Gu Gai Pan over rice, Special #8 (includes color diagrams of installation, 2 sets), Ho, Rania (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - CD-ROM:
      - Sample Work ?
      - Supplemental Materials (includes website www.dancingtoasters.com )
  - Project Proposal: (duplicates 2003 submission), Jevbratt, Lisa (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Project Proposal: Dizzy Atmosphere: Sonic Suspension and Modernist Music (includes installation diagram and sketches), Jones, Jennie C. (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - CD-ROM:
      - Audio CD ??
      - Data CD (includes images)
    - Slides:
      - 10 installation slides
    - Print images:
      - color images of installation, 2 copies
    - Articles:
      - (press and criticism), 2 copies
  - Project Proposal: PlayMaking (includes diagrams, images, printed photos of installations Satellite, Skipping, Variation), Karam, David; and Gigi Obrecht (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - DVD:
      - "Variations"
    - Catalog:
      - SFMOMA Experimental Design Award
    - Pamphlet
  - Project Proposal: Artist (? or no working title), Martinez, Daniel J. (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Video:
      - Animatronic
      - "to make a blind man murder for things he's seen" or "Happiness is over- rated"
    - Journal:
      - Camerawork (includes article on artist and images)
    - Articles:
      - press/criticism
  - Project Proposal: Traffic (includes 2 installation diagrams), McCoy, Jennifer and Kevin (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - DVD:
      - Sample Works: Soft Rains, Pink Light, Every Shot, Horror Chase
    - Catalog:
      - Robotic Films
    - Articles:
      - "Horror Chase" (by the artists), criticism and press
  - Project Proposal: Poet in New York, Merhi, Yucef (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - CD-ROM:
      - Interactive Projects (includes websites "Poetic Dialogue" and "WizArt")
    - Slides:
      - 10 installation slides
    - Websites:
      - Digital Digits: So-H-o-matic
  - Project Proposal: Nica Cart (includes diagram and sketch), Miranda Zuniga, Ricardo (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - CD-ROM:
      - Ricardo Miranda Zuniga
    - Images/Texts:
      - Text descriptions and color diagrams of installations "Nexum ATM," "Public Broadcast Cart," "Vagabonds"
  - Project Proposal: Organum (includes diagram and fictional account of installation experience), Niemeyer, Gregory (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - CD-ROM:
      - Organum Clips
      - Organum Text
      - Organum Samples
      - Extrasensory Perceptions (audio cd) 2 copies
    - DVD:
      - Organum (accompanied by text, "Tour Guide")
    - Articles/Texts:
      - Installation narrative with color illustrations, 2 copies
      - "Breathing Room"
      - "Organum-not a film for humans"
  - Project Proposal: ClassHopper: The Online Game that Explores Class in America, Rinehart, Richard (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Video:
      - Chimera Obscura
    - Website: (May no longer function)
      - Chimera Obscura
    - Catalogue/Gallery Guide:
      - Chimera Obscura, 2 copies
    - Articles:
      - press/criticism
  - Project Proposal: The Secret Life of Words, Rubin, Ben (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - DVD:
      - Spin (doc of installation "Spin")
    - CD-ROM:
      - Listening Post (Not Received)
    - Catalogue:
      - Parachute
      - Listening Post (pamphlet/gallery guide)
    - Articles:
      - press/criticism
    - Photos:
      - doc of installations
    - Website: (May no longer function)
      - EAR Studio project website
  - Project Proposal: Christian Science Interactive Narratives (includes 2 copies of installation diagram), Snibbe, Scott Sona (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Video: